Abhishek Giri

PEGA Certified Senior System Architect

abhishekgiri356@gmail.com | +91 8583906679 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-9iri/

Personal Profile

PEGA Developer with more than 9+ years of experience and dynamic personality with the ability to adapt to a variety of programming languages, techniques and technologies. Ability to work in a group and interact with clients, gather requirements, design and develop Systems that meet exact requirements of them.

Career, growth and learning being the utmost aim, he has been working hard & smart in whichever project assigned. He has shown improvement by achieving the next impossible thing that he thought he couldn't be able to do if it was not for the learning and growth. He has been working in this profession since 2015 however, his current team members have seen the true potential in him and believed in him.

Core Competencies

- · PEGA Development
- · PEGA Deployment manager
- · Ability and desire to learn new technologies
- Teamwork
- · Planning and organizing the assigned work
- · Adaptability to work in high-pressure · Provide application walkthroughs environments
- · Design HDD and Root-Cause Documentation
- · Issue Root-Cause analysis
- · Production BUG fixing
- · Work under Scrum Methodology
- · Production code verification

Tools and Technologies

- · PEGA 7.x and PEGA 8.x
- · PEGA Case management
- · Web Services [REST]

- · SQL Developer
- · Postman
- · Iava

Professional Qualifications

- · PRPC v8, PEGA Certified Senior System Architect, PEGASystems Inc.
- · PRPC v7.1, PEGA Certified System Architect, PEGASystems Inc.

Educational Qualifications

· BCA Graduate in Narula Institute of Technology (2015)

Onsite Exposure

· Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates (2021 - 2022)

Project Responsibilities

- shore teams.
- · Analyze the customer requirements from · Implement the design & development unit the development perspective.
- application requirements.
- · Interact with the client team members to understand the integration of the new functionality into the existing product.
- · Performing several researches to identify · Coordinate the limitations and deficiencies of the proposed technologies, processes methods.
- · Carrying out the development tasks in PEGA PRPC 8.X BPM tool.
- Ensure that the written code meets best Review client release notes and user guides. practices and quality standards
- · Create / update web services requirements · Delivering high quality deliverables to for the application.

- · Serve as senior engineer for on-site and off- · Derive detailed design for the new enhancement and decompose, identify reusable components on System.
 - testing and report test results.
- · Understand business requirements and · Create necessary architecture documents.
 - · Review the defect life-cycle using defect tracking tools and Provide defect resolution on a weekly basis.
 - per-production QA test execution cycles.
 - · Work on the stability and the quality of the application prior to the application release to production.

 - ensure delivery of solutions within the structured timeframe.

Organizational Responsibilities

- · Collaborate with other internal teams (QA team, BA team) efficiently to analyze requirements, milestone planning and deliver solutions in quality and on-time Participated for several peer
- · Provide technical and functional mentorship to new team members
- · Being responsible for the work undertaken.
- · Focus on functionality of the system and code quality.
- · Focus on the first-time-right approach and avoid defects.
- · Working as a team to meet tight deadlines.
- · Worked as a Lead guiding my team members and helping them technically.

Work Experience

	Tavant Technologies, India	September 2023 - Till Date
Architect		
Pega Senior Developer	ATIT - التقنيات المتقدمة لتقنية المعلومات	March 2022 to September 2023
Pega Developer	Capgemini Technology Services, Dubai	December 2020 to March 2022
Associate Consultant	Capgemini Technology Services, India	June 2019 to November 2020
Programmer Analyst	Cognizant Technology Solutions, India	July 2015 to June 2019

Project Experience

Project	Booking.com
Role	PEGA Senior System Architect
Work Location	Kolkata
Duration	September 2023 to Present
Technology	PRPC 8.4, 8.21
Project Description	PEGA-based insurance claim project deals with the customer and their insurance claim for the rental cars.

Project	Ministry of Justice (Taqadhi)
Role	PEGA Senior System Architect
Work Location	Saudi Arabia
Duration	March 2022 to September 2023
Technology	PRPC 8.4, Azue DevOps
Project Description	PEGA-based case management solution with the judicial Taqadhi core court system. It served manual notifications to different case parties at different stages of case proceedings.
Project Responsibilities	PEGA Senior System Architect with the following responsibilities: Carried out the development tasks in Pega PRPC 8.X BPM tool. Review design documents with team members

•	Performed development / Enhancement by understanding existing requirements.
•	Researching some feasibilities of introducing new algorithms to the application.
•	Design discussions with clients and LSA regarding new enhancements.
•	Designed and developed Utility functions.
•	Production defect analyzing and fixing.

Project	Abu Dhabi Executive Office	
Role	PEGA Senior System Architect	
Work Location	Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates	
Duration	December 2020 - March 2022	
Technology	PRPC 8.4, Jira	
Project Description	ADEO application is designed for the Abu Dhabi government, which is responsible for overseeing the development and implementation of strategic initiatives and policies for the Emirate of Abu Dhabi, one of the seven emirates that make up the United Arab Emirates (UAE)	
Project Responsibilities	 PEGA Senior System Architect with the following responsibilities: Manage junior team members and clarify their questions. Review design documents with team members Performed development / Enhancement by understanding existing requirements. Researching some feasibilities of introducing new algorithms to the application. Design discussions with clients and LSA regarding new enhancements Carried out the development tasks in Pega PRPC 8.X BPM tool. 	

Project	Tenaga Nasional Berhad is the largest electricity utility in Malaysia.
Role	PEGA Senior System Architect
Work Location	India
Duration	June 2019 to November 2020
Domain	Energy and Power sector
Technology	PRPC 8.2.1, Jira
Project Description	Tenaga Nasional Berhad (TNB) is the largest electricity utility company in Malaysia, responsible for generating, transmitting, and distributing electricity to customers throughout the country. Pega is a software platform used by TNB to support its business operations and processes. TNB has implemented several Pega applications to manage its customer service, billing and payments, and operations.
Project Responsibilities	 PEGA Senior System Architect with the following responsibilities: Manage junior team members and clarify their questions. Review design documents with team members Performed development / Enhancement by understanding existing requirements. Carried out the development tasks in Pega PRPC 8.X BPM tool. Ensured that the written code meets best practices and quality standards. Decomposed, identified reusable components on the existing system. Implemented the design & development unit testing and reported test results. Coordinated per-production QA test execution cycles for integration changes. Once the application is deployed, provide support.

Project	Royal Bank of Canada (RBC)	
Role	PEGA System Architect	
Work Location	India	
Duration	December 2017 to June 2019	
Domain	Banking & Financing Sector	
Technology	PRPC 7.2, QC (Agile-Scrum)	
Project Description	The primary focus of the RBC application was to upgrade its 10 applications from Pega 5 & 6.2 to 7.2 version upgrade.	
Project Responsibilities	 PEGA System Architect with the following responsibilities: Performed unit testing by understanding existing requirements. Working on the upgrading and optimizing the rules. Carried out the development/defect fixing tasks in Pega PRPC 7.2 BPM tool. Ensured that the written code meets best practices and quality standards. Decomposed, identified reusable components on the existing system. Implemented the design & development unit testing and reported test results. Coordinated per-production QA test execution cycles for integration changes. Once the application is deployed, provide support 	

Project	CITI (STars)
Role	PEGA System Architect
Work Location	India
Duration	October 2016 to December 2017
Domain	Banking and Financing Sector
Technology	PRPC 7.X, QC (Agile-Scrum)
Project Description	CITIBank is a global financial services institution that provides a range of banking, investment, and wealth management services to individuals, businesses, and governments. Citi Bank has implemented Pega's customer engagement and digital process automation platform to improve customer experience, streamline processes, and increase efficiency.
Project Responsibilities	 PEGA System Architect with the following responsibilities: PEGA Web development. PEGA UI upgrade. Took KT sessions from the existing team members regarding the application and the flow. Raised questions regarding all the scenarios possible in order to avoid any requirement gap. Got assigned with the tasks on a daily basis. Completed the assigned tasks within the expected goal time. Got defects and fixed them asap.

Project	HealthNet	
Role	PEGA System Architect	
Work Location	India	
Duration	September 2015 – Oct 2016	
Domain	Health Care	
Technology	PRPC 6.2, QC (Agile-Scrum)	
Project Description	Health Net is a health insurance provider in the United States that has implemented Pega's customer engagement and digital process automation platform to improve its customer experience, streamline its business processes, and increase efficiency.	
Project Responsibilities	 PEGA System Architect with the following responsibilities: Performed development / Enhancement by understanding existing requirements. Carried out the development tasks in Pega PRPC 6.2 BPM tool. Ensured that the written code meets best practices and quality standards. Decomposed, identified reusable components on the existing system. Implemented the design & development unit testing and reported test results. Coordinated per-production QA test execution cycles for integration changes. Once the application is deployed, provide support 	

Declaration

I hereby certify that the above information is true and correct according to the best of my knowledge.

Abhishek Giri